

# Leandro E. Colombo Viña

Professor // Developer



9 Octubre 1981



Larrea 910 8°D, CABA



+54 9 11 3001-5328



http://leo.bitson.com.ar



colomboleandro@bitson.com.ar

# About me ——

Over the last 13 years I've been working on education and since 2013 I've founded BITSON, with other IT professionals, our own democratic & cooperative enterprise. In BITSON we develop free software and free hardware, mainly with access control systems and web applications. I've gained experience in every field related on web applications and access control systems development.

# Skills -Frontend Backend DevOps Linux REST APIS Python

Entrepreneurship\*3 Teaching\*4 Time Management \* 4 Analyst \* 5

(\*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

#### [Interests]

I'm a FLOSS enthusiast. I've been using Free and Open Source Software since 2009. Promoting, attending, participating and organizing events related to FLOSS. I work using the industry best practices like standard coding styles, git-flow, SCRUM, TDD and many others.

#### **Education**

since 2017	Digital Technologies for Education in progress	UNLa
2014-2015	Computer Science Teacher	INSPT-UTN
2011-2014	Applied Informatics Grade point average: 9.29. National flag bearer 2013	INSPT-UTN
2008-2008	Instructor Professional & Labor Trainning.	CFP 34
1995-2000	Electronics Technician	Pío IX (A-66)

### Courses & Certifications

2016	Scrum Grand Master. SCEU-FRBA-UTN
2015	Digital & Social Media Operator. FUNDESCO, Ministry of Labor, Argentina
2015	Remotee worker. FUNDESCO, Ministry of Labor, Argentina
2014	Linux Certified Security System. Carrera Linux Argentina
2013	C Expert. Carrera Linux Argentina
2012	Project Management Executive Program. SCEU-FRBA-UTN
2011	Linux System Administrator Expert. Carrera Linux Argentina
2008	Multimedia products creation. CFP 34

#### **Experience**

2014-hoy

	Project Manager. Software & Hardware develo Trainning.http://www.bitson.com.ar/	pment. Professional
2010-hoy	Associate Professor Teaching 5 courses in the career of Systems A the academic council.	IFTS18 nalysis & Member of
2011-2014	Consultant Networking. GNU/Linux System administration ning.	freelance . Professional Train-
2007-2015	Instructor Python, Networking & GNU/Linux Basics. Educateachers 2.0. Informatics 101.	CFP34 ational Resources for
2010-2014	Community Manager Google Apps for Educations administrator & soo	CFP34 cial media.
2004-2014	SysAdmin / Teacher	Pío IX
2000-2004	Laboratory technician	Celtronics SRL/IMD SRL

Business Development Manager, Founding Partner, Treasurer. BITSON

## Other information

2016	Organizer Python Conference Argentina, Bahía Blanca.	
2015	Founding Partner & Treasurer Python Argentina NGO.	
2014-2015	Speaker at FLISOL http://bitson.com.ar/flisol/git	
2014	Salesian Cooperators Center Manager.	
2010-2012	Conference on Educational Technologies	
2011	Course Continuing Education Professional Technical Education -	
2008	DGEGP Digital Reflex Photography, Digital edition.	